JORDAN ELLIS BECHEK

Chicago IL, US jbechek.github.io bechek.jordan@gmail.com

Software Developer

I am, always have been, and always will be a problem solver and tinkerer, inquisitive in nature and imaginative at heart. I have been programming for twelve years and am skilled in web development, database design, and mobile platform development.

EMPLOYMENT

Oracle Database Developer

May 2019 to Present

Peraton / Northrop Grumman (IT business unit acquired by Peraton in January 2021)

Responsibilities

- Provide support for and optimize performance of production and QA Oracle 19c databases, which facilitate tens of thousands of EDI transactions per day
- Maintain robust ETL structures employing queues, interface tables, and buffer schemas to pull in data, transform it into a digestible state, interrogate it using a set of business rules, and incorporate it into a comprehensive ERP system
- Investigate, debug, and solve production-level issues using PL/SQL to identify errors and develop solutions, including modifying or creating new packages, procedures, functions, and/or DDL
- Satisfy ever-evolving customer needs through paid change controls, overseeing the process from start to finish to avoid scope creep and ensure expectations are clearly defined

Accomplishments

- Led the development of two new ETL systems for new and returning EDI customers
- Designed, developed, and implemented a custom performance logging system, using it to identify inefficient queries and procedures as candidates for optimization
- · Assisted with the development and implementation of a custom archiving solution for all production databases
- Rewrote our set of emergency alert-generating views that poll EDI partners' remote databases to check for missing transactions, eliminating false positives

Computer Systems Analyst

September 2018 to May 2019

Northrop Grumman

Responsibilities

- Developed various data-driven web applications using Adobe ColdFusion to integrate backend Oracle databases
- Developed various tools using Java and BAT scripting to automatically copy, move, and alter EDI files prior to them being processed through EDI maps

Accomplishments

- Led the migration of all our business partners from FTP to SFTP using SSH2 key authentication, heightening server security and privacy for data transmitted
- Created an internal database and web application to house all business contact information in one, easily reference-able place, improving quality of life for business analysts who previously relied on shared Excel spreadsheets

EDI Intern June to September 2018

Northrop Grumman

- Developed and tested new and existing EDI maps to normalize EDI messages in various formats, such as X12, CSV, TSV etc., for introduction into a database
- Worked with EDI partners to resolve translation errors and ensure files were being sent and received in a timely manner
- Aided the EDI team in transitioning from the Gentran legacy system to a more modern B2B framework

Application Support Intern

May to August 2017

Aires

- Developed dynamic, client-facing forms using XML and AJAX
- Supported various Oracle database schemas for customer data using PL/SQL
- Worked closely with not only the Application Support team, but also with QA, Development, and Business teams to ensure clients' issues were solved swiftly and correctly

EDUCATION

Washington & Jefferson College

2014 - 2018

- Bachelor of Art, Computing and Information Studies
 Graduated Magna Cum Laude
- Minors in Neuroscience and Philosophy
- 2016 Recipient of the David and Kristin Steinburg Scholarship in Computing and Information Studies

INDEPENDENT PROJECTS

PROFICIENCY

Student's Edge

Mobile Application

- Developed using Cordova and JQuery Mobile for both iOS and Android
- Allows users to keep track of classes and assignments, and provides a quick and easy
 way of determining how one needs to perform on an upcoming exam to reach a
 user-specified goal based on past performance and exam weighting

My Sunny Day

Mobile Application

- Developed using Cordova and JQuery Mobile for iOS
- Provides a soothing, sunny experience, aimed at helping those who suffer from seasonal affect disorder

Freedom Transit Bus Tracking System

Web Service

- Led the design, development, and implementation of a real-time bus-tracking web service for Freedom Transit
- Android tablets housed on the busses run a custom tracking app, written with Java using Android Studio, that send geolocation data to a Google Firebase JSON database
- A client-facing web application reads from the database and paints an interactive map using the Google Maps API

Minecraft Hue

Game Modification

- Developed a client-side mod and server-side plugin for Minecraft that communicates environmental block data in real-time to the player's Philips Hue smart lights
- This data allows the on-screen experience to be synced with the glow emitted by the lights, and generates visual responses from in-game triggers, such as lightning strikes or walking near a roaring campfire

REFERENCES

Chuck Pfeffer, BS

EDI Manager Peraton 412.314.4129 cpfeffer@opentrac.com

Ryan Brashear, BAS

Software Developer Peraton 412.314.4169

rbrashear@opentrac.com

Charles T. Hannon, PhD

CIS Professor & Department Chair Washington & Jefferson College 724.503.1001 ext. 3402 channon@washjeff.edu

Programming Languages

Oracle SQL (19c, 11g)	HTML5
MySQL	XML
	CSS3
Java	Javascript
C++	JQuery
	JQuery Mobile
Batch	Angular
JSON	

Software

PL/SQL Microsoft Access	Github CVS
	JIRA
Eclipse	Perforce / Helix
NetBeans	
JDeveloper	
Cordova	
XCode	
Android Studio	